[ELECTRONIC MUSIC]
大家好 我是 Rob
ROB DODSON: Hey there polycasters, Rob here.
Polymer 的数据绑定机制中有一个地方让我有些困惑
One of the things that's kind of confused me about Polymer's
那就是如何绑定到对象的子属性
data binding system, is how it binds to sub-properties of objects.
就像你应该可以创建一个
It seems like you should be able to just create
对象和其属性的绑定
a binding on an object and its sub-property,
在 JavaScript 中更新  然后就如你所愿地成功了
and update that in JavaScript, and things would just magically work.
但事实并非那么简单
But reality proves otherwise.
今天我想在 Polycast 中
So today on Polycast what I want to do
谈谈子属性绑定机制是如何工作的
is go through how the sub-property binding system
以及在你的 Polymer 元素中如何做绑定
works and show you how to do bindings in your Polymer elements.
好  让我们开始吧
Let's check it out.
我有一个很简单的元素
So here I've got a pretty simple element
展示了员工对应的经理
for displaying an employee's manager.
我要做的第一件事是
And the first thing I'm going to do
抽取出我们真正关心的内容
is just trim this down to the bits that we really want to focus on.
所以这里只有一段 HTML 和 JavaScript
So we've got just our HTML and just our JavaScript down here.
在这个 div 中
Now, I've got this div and inside of here
我们绑定到了 user.manager
I'm binding to user dot manager.
我正在将它绑定到 user 对象的子属性上
So I'm binding to this sub-property of the user object.
我可以做的是在元素属性里
And what I can do is define that user object here
定义 user 对象
on my elements prototype.
我想让它只要返回一个经理叫 Paul
And I'm just going to have it return this value object that
的 value 对象即可
sets manager equal to Paul.
好  到目前为止都很顺利
So, so far so good.
让我们放一个按钮  用来更改经理
Let me drop in a button, so that I can change this manager.
好了
So I've got this button.
当我按了之后  它会调用 changeManager 函数
And when I tap it, it's going to call change manager.
当我实现这个函数时
And when I implement that function,
它只会将 user.manager 属性
it's just going to set user, this dot user's manager
改为 Fred
property to Fred.
我们期待的是
So we would expect-- over here on the right
右边是我的元素
I've got my element here, we would
我们期待的是按下这个按钮文字也应该更新
expect that when I click this button this should update.
好  让我们点一下
So let's go in there and we'll click it.
好吧  什么都没有发生
And, yeah, nothing happens.
点啊点啊点
I'm just sort of clicking it over and over again,
还是没有变化
not getting anything.
让我们试试别的做法
Well, let's try something else.
与其试图设置子属性
Instead of trying to set the sub-property,
不如用一个新的对象
let's actually just replace the user object
直接换掉 user 对象
with a completely new object.
让我们试一试
Let's go over here and try that.
好  这确实成功了  但这是为什么呢
OK, so that does work, but why?
发生了什么
What is going on here?
区别是什么
Why are they different?
如果你还记得上个视频中
Well, if you remember in the last video,
我提到说  当你创建一个这样的绑定时
I mentioned that when you create a binding like this,
Polymer 会做两件事
Polymer is going to do two things.
它会创建属性的后果
It's going to create property effects
以及创建一个属性的 setter
and it's going to create a setter for that property.
所以在这里  当我彻底替换 user 对象时
So what happens is, when I just completely replace
在这个例子中 setter 被调用了
the user object, in that case the setter is being called
它遍历了所有的属性
and it's running through all of our property effects just
就像其他属性一样
like any other property.
但当我更改对象的子属性时
But when I change a sub-property on that object,
在这个例子中  setter 没有理由被调用
well, in that case there's no reason to call the setter.
因为我没有告诉它 this.user
Because I haven't actually said this dot user
是一个新的东西
equals something new.
setter 没有触发  所以属性的后果
So the setter is not firing, therefore the property effects
没有生效
are not running.
所以 Polymer 看到这样的绑定时
So what Polymer is doing, when it sees this sort of binding,
它创建的是一个路径绑定
is instead of binding directly to that property it's creating
而不是直接绑定到属性
what it calls a path binding.
我们已经有了属性后果
And so we've got this-- we've got these property effects
Polymer 知道了路径
and they know about this path, but we
但我们需要告诉它路径更新了
need to tell the system that the path has updated.
为了做到这一点
And in order to do that, Polymer has actually
Polymer 事实上已经实现了一种叫做 notifyPath 的方法
implemented its own method called notifyPath.
我们可以继续  命令式地
So we can go in and we can imperatively
更改 user.manager 属性
change our user dot manager property,
然后告诉它路径已经更新了
and then we can tell the system that this path right here
然后传入那个值
has updated, and we can pass in that value.
Polymer 将会做的是
And what Polymer is going to go do
检查所有的属性后果
is it's going to look at any of its property effects,
简单地遍历所有属性
it's just going to loop through them,
寻找所有包含这个路径的
it's going to find any of those property effects
属性后果
that have this path inside of them,
然后用特定的值更新这些节点
and it's going to update those nodes with this particular value.
事实上  就像你自然而然
And in fact, since this is such a common task
会想到的一样  Polymer 提供了
that you would do, Polymer actually gives you
一个帮助方法  叫做 this.set
this little helper method called this dot set, which
不光帮你在 JavaScript 中设置了属性
will not only set the property for you in JavaScript,
还帮你调用了 notifyPath
but will also call notifyPath on your behalf.
之所以 Polymer 使用这个方法
Now the reason why Polymer uses this approach,
而不是为所有子属性创建一个 setter
versus creating a setter for all of these sub-properties,
是因为这个代价实在是太高昂了
is that it would just be really, really expensive
如果要为任何对象中的每一个属性
to try and create a setter for every single sub-property
创建 setter 的话
in any object.
你可以想象一下  如果你有一个对象包含 1000 个子属性
You could imagine if you had an object with like 1,000
试着用 setter 来替换所有子属性
sub-properties, that trying to replace all those with setters,
如果你有这些元素的多个实例
if you had multiple instances of those elements
它们又有不同的对象
and they all had different objects,
运行时的代价将会是巨大的
the runtime cost would be pretty massive.
取而代之地  作为易用性和性能
So instead, as kind of a compromise between ease
之间的妥协  我们用这种方法来
of use and performance, we have these methods
进行路径绑定
that allow us to work with these path bindings.
这是命令式的做法
Now this is how you do it imperatively, but let me also
现在让我告诉你如何进行声明式的数据绑定
show you how you can do it declaratively through a data binding.
元素和之前相同
Now, here I've got the same element,
但这次  user.manager 绑定到了这个输入栏
but this time, user dot manager is bound to this paper input
以及上面的 div
field and it's also bound to this div up here.
当我开始输入时
So, when I go and I start typing,
它会同时更新这两个地方
it's going to update that binding in both places.
在 Polymer 底层发生的是
And what's happening is, under the hood when Polymer
输入框正在更新
sees that our paper input is updating,
它检查了这里的这个属性  就像是在说
it checks this property right here and it's like,
我看到这里有一个路径绑定
oh, I see that this is a path binding.
我发现这是结构化的数据
I see that this is some structured data.
帮 user 自动调用 this.set
I'm just going to go ahead and call this dot set
因为我认为
on the user's behalf, because I figure
他们希望我这么做
that's what they wanted to do.
因此你有两种更新子属性的方法
So there's two ways that you can go about updating sub-properties.
你可以用 Polymer 的帮助方法
You can either use Polymer's helper methods
或者某种情形下你恰好
or you can, if you happen to be in a situation
可以这么做  你也可以设置数据绑定
where you can do this, you can also set up data bindings
让它这样做
and have it update that way as well.
现在你已经知道了 Polymer 中
So now you know a bit more about binding to objects
更多的对象绑定
in your Polymer elements.
但还有很多非常有趣的话题
But there's a lot of really cool, meaty topics
我们没有讨论到
which we haven't covered yet, like binding
比如说数组绑定  更改记录  等等
to arrays, and change records, and all that cool stuff.
但我会把这些留到下一集中再讲
But I'm going to save all that for the next episode.
对于那些没想明白U型槽和数据绑定
Now, for those of you who are wondering what a half-pipe has
有什么关系的同学
to do with data bindings.
它们一点关系都没有
Half-pipe has nothing to do with data bindings.
我只是在我办公室边上发现了一个吓人的 U 型槽
I just found a freaking half-pipe next to my office.
这问题大得可怕
This giant chute here.
如果你享受这集的内容的话
So, if you've enjoyed this episode,
或者我们的 U 型槽
you've enjoyed our half-pipe, consider
考虑点击一下订阅按钮
clicking that subscribe button, and maybe catch us
在下一集的 Polycast 见到我们
on the next episode of Polycast.
同样  感谢你们的观看  后会有期
As always, thank you for watching and I'll see you next time.